[Music]
do
hello everyone and welcome to my cottage
it has been an extremely eventful autumn
as you well know after getting engaged
there is suddenly a lot to anticipate
and consider for the future no doubt i
will be experiencing some great changes
in my life in the coming year and so it
has made it clear to me that i really
need to appreciate my time in this sweet
cozy little home
[Music]
recently i decided to experiment with
growing my own mushrooms i love wild
mushrooms especially morels and they
have a very distinct taste that i crave
all year i was told oyster mushrooms are
also delicious and so i decided to pick
up some local grow bags
i have always found mushrooms
fascinating not only do they look
interesting but the way they grow seems
so different from many plants
i imagine if they could talk they would
be quite gentle and unassuming creatures
it takes very little space and water to
grow them every part of the process is
compostable and they don't need any
light they're possibly one of the most
energy efficient things you can grow
they ask so little of the earth and yet
they give so much and are known to have
amazing health benefits
my father was a navy doctor and we lived
in italy for a while and while i was
there i developed a deep appreciation
for simple high quality whole foods and
connecting to the source of what we eat
each season
while in a modern setting depending on
where you live that is understandably
hard to do especially because high
quality ingredients can be expensive and
hard to come by even out here
i'd love to find little ways to connect
with the food i consume and understand
how it grows
even if it's something as simple as
growing sprouts on my windowsill
it's so easy and always delicious
[Music]
one of my favorite things about learning
to use a camera is taking time lapses
something about seeing the way that
things grow always reminds me of the
magic in this world and the way a spore
or seed can sprout an entire life form
is incredible
[Music]
i once read a book on meditations
written by a very wise mystic
in it he described how in the midst of
winter he would walk through a dormant
apple orchard the trees would have no
leaves and look completely dead and yet
when he touched the bark and put his
face up close he could smell the apples
the essence of the fruit was deep inside
in the core and roots of the tree
even in the dead of winter there was
life
that tree held within a thousand apples
they just hadn't been formed yet
i like to apply that idea to our own
spirits how we have within us so much
potential for giving
in my case i like to imagine a seed of
light inside my heart during this time
of year when the days are quickly
getting darker almost like holding a
single star that reflects the night sky
i need to take care of that star and not
let anything suppress its light
it is a thought that i use to inspire my
meditations
perhaps it is something that will
inspire you as you reach the end of the
year and begin to think about the
possibilities of the next
perhaps we don't need to set any
particular goal for the future only to
dedicate ourselves to tending the light
we hold within and do whatever we need
in order to let it shine the greater
[Music]
do
so
[Music]
as you can see i've been spending a lot
of time on my porch stargazing and i've
become infatuated with the night sky as
of late
i swear moon bunnies are dancing around
in my head as i speak
thank you for indulging my nighttime
musings i hope you have a lovely day or
night
take care
you